<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Gooooooooooood</title>
  <icon>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/eb4ac5c946da3c1711e5ecff20d94b87</icon>
  
  <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-12-13T13:42:56.769Z</updated>
  <id>https://xuduokuaile.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Xu</name>
    <email>1361696007@qq.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Translation</title>
    <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/13/Translation/"/>
    <id>https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/13/Translation/</id>
    <published>2021-12-13T06:54:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-13T13:42:56.769Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="第一篇"><a href="#第一篇" class="headerlink" title="第一篇"></a>第一篇</h1><p>类似的可能还有毛笔，扇子，镜子等话题。篇幅问题，我就给大家一个。</p><p>筷子(chopsticks ）是中国传统的独具特色的进食工具（dining utensils），至今已有数千年的历史。筷子在古代被称为 “箸”，大约从明朝开始才有了 “筷子 ”的称呼。筷子多为竹子制成，也有用木头、象牙（ ivory）、金属或其他材料制作而成。它要么上方下圆，要么上下全圆而上粗下细。不管其形状如何，筷子必须是成对使用的，并且两只筷子的大小长短要相同。筷子是中国人日常生活的必备工具，它的发明充分反映了中国人民的智慧。</p><p>Chopsticks, with a history of thousands of years, are unique traditional Chinese dining utensils. They were called “zhu” in ancient China and the name of “Kuai Zi” began to be used in Ming Dynasty. Chopsticks are usually made of bamboo. Some are made of wood, ivory, metals or other materials. Their upper parts are squar e and lower parts round, or they are all round with thicker upper parts and thinner lower parts. Whatever their shapes are, they are used in pairs and the pair must be identical to each other. Chopsticks are the necessary dining utensils in Chinese people’s daily life, the invention of which fully displays the intelligence of Chinese people.</p><h1 id="第二篇"><a href="#第二篇" class="headerlink" title="第二篇"></a>第二篇</h1><p>黄梅戏</p><p>类似的还有“京剧”“昆曲”都算，篇幅问题就给大家一篇</p><p>黄梅戏(Huangmei Opera)源于湖北省黄梅县的采茶歌曲，连同京剧、越剧 (Yue Opera)、评剧(Ping Opera)和豫剧(Yu Opera)是中国的五大戏曲。它最初是以一种简单的载歌载舞的戏剧形式出现的。后来，随着饱受洪水灾害的灾民，黄梅戏传到了安徽省安庆市。它吸收了徽剧和当地歌舞的元素，发展到了今天的形式。黄梅戏以一种淸新的风格反映了普通居民的生活，受到了群众的喜爱。</p><p>Huangmei Opera was originated from tea picking songs in Huangmei county,Hubei province. It is one of the Five Operas in China together with Beijing Opera, Yue Opera, Ping Opera and Yu Opera. It first appeared as a simple drama of song and dance.Later, it was spread to Anqing, Anhui Province by immigrating victims of floods. Absorbing elements of Anhui Opera and local songs and dances, Huangmei Opera was developed to the present form. It enjoys great popularity among the masses by reflecting the life of ordinary people in a fresh style.</p><h1 id="第三篇"><a href="#第三篇" class="headerlink" title="第三篇"></a>第三篇</h1><p>水稻</p><p>可能也会考杂交水稻，但是我感觉还是水稻的可能性大一些，类似的还有“小麦”等话题</p><p>在中国，水稻生产是国民经济的重要组成部分，中国人早在公元前4000年就开始了水稻种植，而后逐渐传播到世界各地。目前，中国是世界上最大的水稻生产国，水稻产量占世界产量的26%。我国水稻主要种植于长江沿岸及南方各省份，米饭是中国人，特别是南方人，非常重要的主食。此外，水稻还可以用来酿酒、制糖及用作工业原料。</p><p>In China,rice production is an important part of the national economy.As early as 4,000 B.C.,the Chinese started rice cultivation which later gradually spread all over the world.At present,China is the world’s largest producer of rice,producing 26% of the world rice output.The rice crop in China grows primarily in provinces along the Yangtze River and in the South.Rice is an important staple food for Chinese,particularly the southerners.In addition,rice can be used to make wine and sugar and used as industrial materials.</p><h1 id="第四篇"><a href="#第四篇" class="headerlink" title="第四篇"></a>第四篇</h1><p>类似的可能还有“垃圾分类”等话题</p><p>低碳生活 (low -carbon life) 对于我们普通人来说是一种态度，我们应该积极提倡并去实践，从自己做起，从节约水电这些点滴做起。除了植树，有的人买运输里程很短的商品，还 有人坚持爬楼梯，形 形色色，非 常有趣。“低碳生活”的理念逐渐被世界各国所接受。低碳生活的出现不仅告诉人们可以为减碳做些什么，还告诉人们可以怎么做。在这种生活方式逐渐兴起的时候，大家开始关心自己每天是否为减碳做了什么。</p><p>Low-carbon life is an attitude for ordinary people, an d we should actively advocate and practice low -carbon life by doing it from ourselves and by starting bit by bit from saving water and electricity. Beside s planting trees, some peoplepurchase goods within a short delivery distance and others stick to climbing stairs.People do various things to live a low -carbon life, whic h is really interesting. “Lo w-carbon life “concep t has gradually been accepted worldwi de. The emergence of low -carbon lifestyle not only introduces to people what they can do for carbon reduction,but also tells them how they can do it. As this lifestyle gradually becomes popular,people begin to ask themselves whether they have contributed something to carbon reduction every day.</p><h1 id="第五篇"><a href="#第五篇" class="headerlink" title="第五篇"></a>第五篇</h1><p>中医，也称汉医，是指以中国汉族创造的传统医学为主的医学，是研究人体以及疾病的诊断和防治等<br>的一门学科。早在两千多年前，中医专著《黄帝内经》问世，奠定了中医学的基础。中医具有完整的理论<br>体系，认为人体各个器官共处于一个统一体中互相联系的。其诊法不同于现代医疗，包括传统的望闻问切。<br>经过几千年的临床实践，证实了中国的中医中药无论是在治病上、在防病上，还是在养生上，都是确凿有<br>效可行的。</p><p>Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM), also known as Han medicine, refers to the traditional medicine<br>created by the Han nationality in China. It is a discipline that studies human as well as the diagnosis and<br>treatment of diseases. As early as 2,000 years ago, the Yellow Emperor’s Neijing, a masterpiece of<br>Chinese medicine called,Huang Di Nei Jing, published. It has laid the foundation of traditional Chinese<br>medicine. Traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) has a complete theoretical system, which believes that<br>the various organs of the human body are in a unity, and they are interrelated with each other. Its<br>diagnosis method is different from the modern medical treatment, including the traditional observation,<br>listening, asking and measuring.Through thousands of years of clinical practice, it has been proved that<br>Chinese traditional Chinese medicine is effective and feasible in curing diseases, preventing diseases<br>and maintaining health. </p><h1 id="第六篇"><a href="#第六篇" class="headerlink" title="第六篇"></a>第六篇</h1><p>网课是一种新兴的学习方式，是为学习者提供的以互联网为平台、内容包含视频、图片、文<br>字互动等多种形式的系列学习教程。区别于线下课堂教授，网课具有灵活便捷的优点。越来越多<br>的学生群体和父母的开始使用。一场突如其来的疫情暴发，打乱了我们的生活节奏，但是在当今<br>在线教育的帮助下，学习者可以通过在家上网学习，只要有网的地方，即可利用碎片化的时间学<br>习；农村家庭的学生也可通过互联网在接受正规免费的课程教育，让他们“停课不停学、学习不<br>延期”。<br>Online course is an emerging way of learning. It is a series of learning courses provided<br>for learners with the Internet as the platform, including video, pictures, text interaction and<br>other forms of learning. Being different from the offline classroom teaching, online course has<br>a lot of advantages, such as flexible and convenient . More and more students groups and<br>parents began to use. A sudden outbreak of the epidemic has disrupted our pace of life. However, with the help of online education, learners can study online at home, as long as there<br>is a network. They can use the fragmented time to learn. Students from rural families can also<br>receive formal and free courses via the Internet, allowing them to suspend their classes<br>without postponing their studies.</p><h1 id="第七篇"><a href="#第七篇" class="headerlink" title="第七篇"></a>第七篇</h1><p>杂交水稻简单来说,就是不同品种水稻之间的交配。 这种水稻具备不同品种的优点。 可以毫不夸张<br>地说,假如没有袁隆平研制出的杂交水稻,世界上还会有很多人饿死。 中国是一个人多地少的国家,粮食生产<br>历来是关系国计民生的大事。 在中国,现在杂交水稻已不是百姓常吃的大米,因杂交水稻追求的是产量而不<br>是口感。 中国发明的杂交水稻,除国内发展迅速外,在国外,已有越南 印度尼西亚 菲律宾和美国在大面积应<br>用,并取得了显著的增产效果。<br>Hybrid rice is simply the interbreeding of different varieties of rice.This rice has the<br>advantages of different varieties. It is no exaggeration to say that if it were not for the hybrid rice<br>developed by Yuan Longping, many people in the world would starve to death.China is a country<br>with more people and less land. Grain production has always been a major issue related to the<br>national economy and people’s livelihood. In China, hybrid rice is no longer the common rice to<br>eat, because it pursues yield rather than taste.In addition to the rapid development of China’s<br>hybrid rice, in foreign countries, like Vietnam, Indonesia, the Philippines and the United States<br>hybrid rice has been used in large-scale, and has achieved </p><hr><h1 id="第一篇相似"><a href="#第一篇相似" class="headerlink" title="第一篇相似"></a>第一篇相似</h1><p>毛笔，是一种源于中国的传统书写工具，也逐渐成为传统绘画工具。毛笔是汉族人民在生产实践中发明的。随着人类社会的不断发展，勤劳智慧的汉民族又不断地总结经验，存其精华，弃其糟粕，勇于探索，敢于创新。几千年以来，它为创造汉族民族光辉灿烂的文化，为促进汉民族与世界各族的文化交流，做出了卓越的贡献。毛笔是汉民族对世界艺术宝库提供的一件珍宝。</p><p>　　【参考译文】</p><p>　　Writing brush, a traditional writing tool originated from China, has also gradually become a traditional painting tool. Writing brush was invented by the Han people during their production practice. With the constant development of human society, the diligent and intelligent Han people kept summing up the experience. Discarding the dross while assimilating the essence, they strive to explore and blaze new trails. Over thousands of years, writing brush has made great contribution to creating the splendid culture of the Han people and to promoting the cultural exchange between people of all nationalities and the Han people. Writing brush is a treasure that the Han people have provided the world’s arts treasure house.</p><p>在中国，扇子的使用始于数千年前。扇子是由许多不同的材料制成的。汉、唐期间，农业有了发展，丝绸和缎面(satin)扇子开始出现，并在文人雅士 (scholars and artists)中成为了一种时尚。他们通过在扇面上书写和绘画来展示自己的才能。扇子很快获得了非常大的社会意义。它们成为了有学问的人标准夏季着装的一部分。中国制作的扇子多种多样。它们如今依旧享有盛誉。</p><p>　　参考翻译:</p><p>　　Fans began to be used in China thousands of years ago. They were made out of many different materials. During the Han and Tang Dynasties, due to progress in agriculture, silk and satin fans appeared, and they became a fashion among scholars and artists who showed their genius by writing and painting on the fans. Fans soon acquired considerable social significance. They became a part of the standard summer costume among the learned. A great variety of fans have been produced in China and they still enjoy great reputation today.</p><hr><h1 id="水稻的那篇极有可能考"><a href="#水稻的那篇极有可能考" class="headerlink" title="水稻的那篇极有可能考"></a>水稻的那篇极有可能考</h1><p>水稻<br>1.找主干（1.谁 是 什么  2谁 做 什么 3 什么 被做）<br>2. 添枝加叶<br>3. 检查回读</p><h2 id="中文"><a href="#中文" class="headerlink" title="中文"></a>中文</h2><p>水稻（大米），是中国人日常饮食中的主角之一，是中国南方主食。米饭营养丰富，几乎可以供给全身所需营养。大米饭含有人体90%的必需营养元素，且各种营养素十分均衡，所以是最佳主食。米饭的面世，可追溯至粥。中国人用筷子吃米饭，用勺子喝粥。如果（我们，你）掌握吃米饭的健康原则，日积月累，不知不觉就(它)能起到防病抗衰的作用，对身体极为有益。 </p><h2 id="译文"><a href="#译文" class="headerlink" title="译文"></a>译文</h2><p>Main food<br>的 of  A of B    B的A<br>水稻（大米），是中国人日常饮食中的主角之一，是中国南方主食。</p><p>Rice is one of the main roles of Chinese daily foods and is the staple food in southern China. </p><p>米饭营养丰富，几乎可以供给全身所需营养。</p><p>Richly nutritious rice can almost provide nutrition to the whole body.<br>Rice has rich nutrition and it can almost provide nutrition to the whole body.<br>With rich nutrients, rice can almost provide nutrition to the whole body.<br>营养: good thing to our body</p><p>大米饭含有人体90%的必需营养元素，且各种营养素十分均衡，所以是最佳主食。<br>Rice contains 90% of necessary nutrients of human body. What’s more, the nutrients are well balanced. Therefore, rice the the best staple food.<br>Rice is the best staple food, because it contains 90% of necessary nutrients of human body and the nutrients are well balanced.</p><p>米饭的面世，可追溯至粥。<br>Goes back to<br>Be traced back to<br>The emergence of rice can be traced back to the porridge.</p><p>Chopsticks   spoon<br>中国人用筷子吃米饭，用勺子喝粥。<br>Chinese people eat rice with chopsticks and drink porridge with spoon.</p><p>如果（我们，你）掌握吃米饭的健康原则，日积月累，不知不觉就(它)能起到防病抗衰的作用，对身体极为有益。<br>的 of  A of B    B的A  A 和B 都是名词  是动词 ving</p><p>If we master the healthy principle of eating rice, with time goes by, it can unconsciously play a role in preventing disease and aging and is extremely beneficial to our body.</p><p>Rice (rice), one of the main characters in Chinese daily diet, is the staple food in southern China. Rich in nutrients, rice can provide almost all the nutrients needed for the whole body. Rice is the best staple food because it contains 90% of the essential nutrients in the human body and is well balanced. Rice can be traced back to porridge. Chinese people eat rice with chopsticks and porridge with spoons. If you master the healthy principle of eating rice, over a long period of time, you will unconsciously play a role in disease prevention and aging, which is extremely beneficial to the body.</p><h1 id="人工智能"><a href="#人工智能" class="headerlink" title="人工智能"></a>人工智能</h1><p>人工智能是一门极富挑战性的科学，从事这项工作的人必须懂得计算机知识，心理学和哲学。 总的说来，人工智能研究的一个主要目标是使机器能够胜任一些通常需要人类智能才能完成 的复杂工作。但不同的时代、不同的人对这种“复杂工作”的理解是不同的。人工智能的传说可以追溯到古埃及，但随着1941年以来电子计算机的发展，技术已最终可以创造出机器智能。工智能就其本质而言，是对人的思维的信息过程的模拟，但是它们的智能在许多方面会远远超过人脑。</p><p>人工智能是一门极富挑战性的科学，<br>1.找主干（1谁是什么 谁做什么 什么被做）<br>AI（artificial intelligence）is a science<br>2.添枝加叶 （修饰成分）<br>的 形容词— challenging<br>AI（artificial intelligence）is an extremely challenging science。<br>Of  A OF B  B的A<br>的 定语从句  -如果修饰成分有动词<br>AI（artificial intelligence）is a science, which is full of challenges。<br>检查回读<br>从事这项工作的人必须懂得计算机知识，心理学和哲学。<br>People, who do this job, must know computer knowledge, psychology and philosophy.</p><p>3.<br>nable sb to do<br>总的说来，人工智能研究的一个主要目标是使机器能够胜任一些通常需要人类智能才能完成 的复杂工作。<br>Generally speaking, one of the main purposes of AI research is to enable machines to do some complex jobs, which usually require human intelligence. </p><p>1 找主干（1谁是什么 谁做什么 什么被做）</p><p>但不同的时代、不同的人对这种“复杂工作”的理解是不同的。<br> People’s understandings towards such “complex job” in different times are different.<br> People’s understandings towards such “complex job” in different times vary.<br>人工智能的传说可以追溯到古埃及，<br>但随着 1941 年以来电子计算机的发展，技术已最终可以创造出机器智能。<br>Goes back to<br>Be traced back to<br>The legend of AI can be traced back to the ancient Egypt.<br>However, with the development of electric computer since 1941, the technology can create finally machine intelligence. </p><p>人工智能就其本质而言，是对人的思维的信息过程的模拟，但是它们的智能在许多方面会远远超过人脑。<br>Speaking of its essence,<br>AI is the simulation of information process of human thinking.<br> A OF B OF C<br>C 的 B的  A<br>However, its intelligence will surpass human brain in many aspects. </p><p>Artificial intelligence is a challenging science. People who work on it must know computer science, psychology and philosophy. In general, a major goal of artificial intelligence research is to enable machines to perform complex tasks that would normally require human intelligence. However, people from different times have different understandings of this “complex work”. The legend of artificial intelligence can be traced back to ancient Egypt. But with the development of electronic computers since 1941, technology can finally create machine intelligence.Artificial intelligence, by its very nature, is the simulation of the information process of human thinking, but their intelligence will far surpass human brains in many aspects.</p><h1 id="瓷器"><a href="#瓷器" class="headerlink" title="瓷器"></a>瓷器</h1><p>中国是瓷器的故乡，瓷器是中国劳动人民的一个重要的创造。瓷器的发明是中华民族对世界文明的伟大贡献，在英文中“瓷器（china）”与中国（China）同为一词。大约在公元前16世纪的商代中期，中国就出现了早期的瓷器。原始瓷器起源于3000多年前。至宋代时，名瓷名窑已遍及大半个中国，是瓷业最为繁荣的时期。中国历来有三大瓷都的说法，分别是江西景德镇、福建泉州市德化县、湖南醴陵市。</p><p>1.的 -找形容词 —= 美丽的 帅气的<br>2.A Of b  b的A   ab<br>3.修饰成分有动词 用定语从句<br>1.找主干（1.谁是 什么 2 谁做什么 3 什么被做）<br>2.添枝加叶（添加修饰成分）<br>3.检查回读</p><p>中国是瓷器的故乡，瓷器是中国劳动人民的一个重要的创造。<br>China is the hometown of porcelain, which is an important creation of Chinese working people.</p><p>4.找主干（1.谁是 什么 2 谁做什么 3 什么被做）<br>5.添枝加叶（添加修饰成分）<br>6.检查回读</p><p>瓷器的发明是中华民族对世界文明的伟大贡献，<br>The invention of porcelain is a great contribution of Chinese people to the world civilization.</p><p>在英文中“瓷器（china）”与中国（China）同为一词。<br>In English, the words: china and China are the same word. </p><p>大约在公元前16世纪的商代中期，中国就出现了早期的瓷器。<br>The early porcelain had appeared in China around BC 16th century in the middle of Shang Dynasty.</p><p>原始瓷器起源于3000多年前。<br>Primitive porcelain originated from over 3000 years ago.<br>Spread<br>至宋代时，名瓷名窑已遍及大半个中国，是瓷业最为繁荣的时期。<br>Until Song dynasty, famous porcelains and famous manufacturers had been spread throughout more than half of China.<br> Song dynasty is the most prosperous period of porcelain.<br>    Best<br>中国历来有三大瓷都的说法，分别是江西景德镇、福建泉州市德化县、湖南醴陵市。<br>In China ,there has always been a saying that the three biggest capitals of porcelain are Jingdezhen in Jiangxi, Dehua in Quanzhou, Zhejiang and Liling city in Hunan.</p><p>China is the hometown of porcelain, which is an important creation of the Chinese working people. The invention of porcelain is a great contribution of the Chinese nation to world civilization. In English, “China” and “China” are the same word. Early porcelain appeared in China around the middle of the Shang Dynasty in the 16th century BC. Primitive porcelain originated more than 3,000 years ago. By the Song Dynasty, famous porcelain kilns had spread throughout more than half of China, which was the most prosperous period of porcelain industry. Jingdezhen, Jiangxi province, Dehua County, Quanzhou City, Fujian Province and Liling City, Hunan Province are the three capitals of porcelain in China.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;第一篇&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#第一篇&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;第一篇&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;第一篇&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;类似的可能还有毛笔，扇子，镜子等话题。篇幅问题，我就给大家一个。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;筷子(chopsticks ）是中国传统的独具特色的</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="English Learning" scheme="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Writting Skill for Band 6</title>
    <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/10/writting-skill-in-Band-6/"/>
    <id>https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/10/writting-skill-in-Band-6/</id>
    <published>2021-12-10T09:01:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-13T13:52:54.938Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="1-find-writting-task"><a href="#1-find-writting-task" class="headerlink" title="1 find writting task"></a>1 find writting task</h2><p>why?, what? or how? .</p><hr><h2 id="2-beginning"><a href="#2-beginning" class="headerlink" title="2 beginning"></a>2 beginning</h2><h3 id="2-1矛盾"><a href="#2-1矛盾" class="headerlink" title="2.1矛盾"></a>2.1矛盾</h3><p>The last few years have witnessed the trend of…  +状语—时间地点原因目的//背景 加一些个性化的东西，this increasingly globalised world<br>When it comes to whether…, people harbour divergent viewpoints on… .  //双方 注意主题同义替换<br>Some believe that … , while others hold the idea that … . //具体<br>However, from my perspective,  I stand for the former/latter one. //我的观点 </p><h3 id="2-2重要性"><a href="#2-2重要性" class="headerlink" title="2.2重要性"></a>2.2重要性</h3><p>The last few years have witnessed the trend of… +状语—时间地点原因目的//背景<br>Were it not for …, … would be seriously undermined. //要不是…(if it were not)，…将会受到极大影响。<br>Were it not for …, it would be harder for to //要不是…(if it were not)，将很难做..。<br>Nothing is more principle than… //什么是十分重要的</p><h3 id="2-3名言"><a href="#2-3名言" class="headerlink" title="2.3名言"></a>2.3名言</h3><p>The last few years have witnessed the trend of… +状语—时间地点原因目的//背景<br>As a famous saying/proverb goes，… //谚语<br>From my perspective, this proverb tell us that we cannot … unless … // 我们不能…，除非…</p><h3 id="2-4社会现象"><a href="#2-4社会现象" class="headerlink" title="2.4社会现象"></a>2.4社会现象</h3><p>It is quite common for sb. to do sth+ 状语—时间地点原因目的//背景<br>To illustrate, we can often that… //简而言之<br>Obviously, this issue has already given rise to a lot of public concerns so </p><h3 id="2-5漫画"><a href="#2-5漫画" class="headerlink" title="2.5漫画"></a>2.5漫画</h3><p>As is explicitly demonstrated in the cartoon, A is doing … and B say with doubt/certainty/irony … //正如漫画清楚描述的那样,A…B迟疑地/确定地/讽刺地回复<br>Then, A looks embarrassed/frustrated/disappointed. //A看起来很尴尬/沮丧/不开心<br>Apparently, this cartoon aims to tell us that in order to …, sb should … </p><h3 id="2-6图表"><a href="#2-6图表" class="headerlink" title="2.6图表"></a>2.6图表</h3><p>The line/bar/pie chart illustrae how many … from … in … to … in …<br>From the marked/sharp rise/decline in the chart, it goes without saying that</p><hr><hr><p>三篇模板</p><h2 id="第一篇"><a href="#第一篇" class="headerlink" title="第一篇"></a>第一篇</h2><p>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write a composition on the topic “The advantages and disadvantages of online course”.</p><p>除了网课，网络和科技相关的话题也有可能考到，但是换汤不换药，按照我讲的结构写就OK。六级写作最好能举一个例子</p><p>（其实网课之前考过，不排除不会再考，只是形式会变换）</p><p>It has been widely noted that the Internet has penetrated every aspect of our daily life and exerted a huge impact on our study.Online course which is held by many to be an indispensable tool,has captured public attention.</p><p>As regards to the social implication of Online course,my discussion on the issue is mainly twofold.On the one hand,due to the outbreak of the novel coronavirus, the city where I lived was on lockdown. We needed to be quarantined at home. However, the Internet allowed us to take online courses, bringing much convenience to our education.Thus studying online is a wise choice to meet the needs of offline learning.On the other hand,Online course only suits students with good self-control instead of those who have difficulty in self-discipline.Meanwhile,it relies too much on media, which can easily divert students’ attention from their study.Finally,it’s difficult for learners to organize teamwork and develop impersonal relationships through distance learning.</p><p>To sum up, it is of great benefit for us to attend online course reasonably and learn how to make the most of it.Specifically,The fundamental way in which the school should make full use of the advantages of network courses to promote the all-round development of students.</p><h2 id="第二篇"><a href="#第二篇" class="headerlink" title="第二篇"></a>第二篇</h2><p>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write a composition on the topic“How to Balance Compulsory and Selective Courses”</p><p>In view of students’ comprehensive development, most universities offer a wide range of selective courses as the complement to compulsory courses.</p><p>However, this well-intentioned design brings about some unexpected problems. One problem to note is that despite the freedom to choose what to learn, students are still required to complete the selective courses with credits, which means they have to put in extra energy and time in order to meet the requirements. This gives rise to a problem of how to strike a balance between compulsory and selective course and many complaints are heard among college students who find it hard to struggle for excellent performance in both selective courses and compulsory courses.</p><p>From my point of view, the key to this problem lies in the time management. All that a student needs to do is to make the time distribution between the study of compulsory and selective courses more reasonable. When there is a scientifically-arranged schedule to follow, I believe students will do better when facing the academic challenges, be it compulsory or selective courses.</p><h2 id="第三篇"><a href="#第三篇" class="headerlink" title="第三篇"></a>第三篇</h2><p>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write a composition on the importance of persistence/cooperation/optimism.（价值观方面，例如个人努力，个人习惯，沟通表达等）</p><p>In such a competitive society,it goes without saying that persistence is of utmost importance in our study and life. persistence has become an integral part for great achievements and this character has obviously shaped our culture and destiny in quite an obvious manner.</p><p>As regards the social implication of this spirit, my discussion is generally twofold.On the one hand,against the backdrop of ruthless and fierce competition,persistence is truly the fundamental attribute of top performers,which separates the high achievers from the rest of the pack.On the other hand,persistence can not only enable us to ameliorate ourselves so that we can be qualified for future career promotion,but also make us be ready for meeting the for the coming challenges.We students should never give up our dreams in face of hardship.For example Chinese scientist Tu Youyou,the first Chinese female Nobel Prize winner,managed to combined traditional Chinese medicine and western medicine innovatively to obtain the pure substance qinghaosu.if she had given up when she were confronted with challenges.It is no exaggeration to say that It was unswerving persistence that made her become one of the greatest scientists in human history.</p><p>To sum up,we can come to the conclusion that the persistence is of equal importance in personal and social progress.</p><hr><h1 id="图表"><a href="#图表" class="headerlink" title="图表"></a>图表</h1><p>1.For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write an essay based on the graph below. You should start your essay with a brief description of the graph and comment on China’s population structure.You should write at least 150 words but no more than 200 words</p><p><img src="https://github.com/xuduokuaile/xuduokuaile.github.io/blob/master/img/%E5%9B%BE%E8%A1%A8.png?raw=true" alt="图表"></p><p>As is starkly mirrored in the diagram（表格）that Chinese  population of elder is expected to grow rapidly in the following decades.  Old people in China will become more and more.</p><p>It is revealed that more Chinese people are getting older, and it is unhealthy.  （图片内涵）The following reasons can account for this issue.（过渡句）<br>In the first place, there is no doubt that one child policy had played an important role in this process. Based on big data, most of the elderly citizens involved have admitted that they were only allowed to have one child when they were young.<br> Moreover，no one can deny that the pressure of living is indeed huge nowadays.Where there is pressure, there are less incentives to raise children. Last but not least, I firmly believe that younger citizens should shoulder the responsibility of the future.The harder they work，the stronger our country will be.</p><p>In conclusion, the demographic structure of our country is getting older. However, if we spare no effort to face the challenge and work hard, the future of our country will be both hopeful and rosy.</p><p>Writing(30 minutes) （问题解决）<br>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write an essay on the importance of mental health and how to keep mental health. You should write at least 150 words but no more than 200 words.<br>第一段：重要性（学生压力大，心理疾病的人越来越多）（对于每个公民来说保持心理健康非常有必要）（过渡句：以下解决方案可以）<br>第二段：1.开设心理课（学校应该提供义务心理课程）<br>2.心理咨询（在学校设立心理咨询服务对于学生心理健康是很有帮助的<br>3.我们应该保持一个乐观的生活态度.（即使生活有很多困难，办法总比困难多）<br>With the rapid development of society, there is an increasing number of students, who suffered from mental diseases, resulting from ever-growing pressure. It is of great necessity for every citizen to keep mental health. The following solutions can account for this issue.<br>First and foremost, there is no doubt that the school should provide compulsory and free psychology courses. Based on a most recent survey, a majority of successful social elites admitted that they enjoyed a psychology course on the campus. Furthermore, it is clear that setting up free psychological counseling service is helpful for maintaining the mental health of students. Where there is counseling, there is communication. Last but not least, no one can deny that we should hold an optimistic attitude towards life. Although life is full of difficulties, there are more solutions than problems.<br>In a word, keeping mental health is crucial for everyone. If we try our utmost to be optimistic, the future of our life will be both promising and rosy.</p><p>Writing(30 minutes) (观点选择)<br>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write an essay on whether to do the part time job in school. You should write at least 120 words but no more than 180 words.<br>1.做兼职工作可以给我们提供实践经验，这是不能从书本或课堂上获得的。<br>根据最近的一项调查，大多数成功的社会精英承认他们从兼职工作中获得的实践经验获益匪浅。<br>2.此外，没有人能否认我们可以通过兼职工作挣些额外的钱。有多余的钱，就有更多有趣的事情可以做。<br>3.做兼职工作可以培养我们的能力。虽然会占用一些学习时间，但对我们学生来说，提高自己的能力是很有必要的。<br>With the rapid development of education, nowadays students have different options for a part time job. Some think that doing a part time job in school is beneficial, while others think that focusing on studying only is a better choice. Personally, I prefer the former one. The following reasons can account for my preference.<br>First and foremost, doing a part time job can offer us practical experience, which cannot be gained from the book or classroom. Based on a most recent survey, most successful social elites admitted that they benefited a lot from the practical experience gained from part time jobs. Furthermore, no one can deny that we can earn some extra money from the part time job. Where there is extra money, there are more fun things to do. Last but not least, it is clear that doing a part time job can cultivate our abilities. Although some study time will be occupied, it is of great necessity for us students to improve our abilities.<br>In a word, doing a part time job is beneficial for students in the university. If we try our utmost to do it reasonably, the future of our life will be both promising and rosy.</p><p>Writing(30 minutes)(谚语类)<br>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write an essay on commenting on a saying “one ant-hole may cause the collapse of a huge Dam”. You should write at least 150 words but no more than 200 words.<br>（解读：细节的重要性）<br>1.忽视细节影响人设（如果你忽视细节，别人会用不一样的方式对待你）.<br>2.细节中蕴含机会<br>3.细节决定成败。<br>As an old saying goes：one ant-hole may cause the collapse of a huge Dam. For us college students, it has an increasingly important significance: the details play an important role on the whole. The following reasons can account for this issue.<br>First and foremost, there is no doubt that people will treat you differently if you neglect the details. Based on a most recent survey, most social elites admitted that they hate to work with people who neglect the details. Furthermore, no one can deny that the opportunity comes from the details. Where there are details, there are innovations. Last but not least, it is obvious that success or failure is decided by the details. Although details are small, they can be key to the whole issue.<br>In a word, it is of great necessity for us to pay attention to the details. If we try our utmost to complete the small details, the future of our life will be both promising and rosy.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-find-writting-task&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-find-writting-task&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;1 find writting task&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;1 find writting task&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="English Learning" scheme="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Start Hexo</title>
    <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/08/start-hexo/"/>
    <id>https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/08/start-hexo/</id>
    <published>2021-12-08T12:59:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-12T12:17:54.963Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Start-Hexo"><a href="#Start-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="Start Hexo"></a>Start Hexo</h1><h2 id="1-cd-the-url-of-hexo"><a href="#1-cd-the-url-of-hexo" class="headerlink" title="1. cd the url of hexo"></a>1. cd the url of hexo</h2><p>cd the url of hexo</p><h2 id="2-hexo-s"><a href="#2-hexo-s" class="headerlink" title="2. hexo s"></a>2. hexo s</h2><hr><h1 id="Writing-an-Article"><a href="#Writing-an-Article" class="headerlink" title="Writing an Article"></a>Writing an Article</h1><h2 id="1-创建新的文件"><a href="#1-创建新的文件" class="headerlink" title="1.创建新的文件"></a>1.创建新的文件</h2><p>hexo n  + 文章名</p><h2 id="2-编写内容"><a href="#2-编写内容" class="headerlink" title="2.编写内容"></a>2.编写内容</h2><p>最好使用 markdown 格式</p><h2 id="3-清理缓存文件"><a href="#3-清理缓存文件" class="headerlink" title="3.清理缓存文件"></a>3.清理缓存文件</h2><p>hexo clean</p><h2 id="4-生成静态文件"><a href="#4-生成静态文件" class="headerlink" title="4.生成静态文件"></a>4.生成静态文件</h2><p>hexo g</p><hr><h1 id="Link-to-GitHub"><a href="#Link-to-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Link to GitHub"></a>Link to GitHub</h1><h2 id="1-远端：github"><a href="#1-远端：github" class="headerlink" title="1.远端：github"></a>1.远端：github</h2><h3 id="1-1创建仓库"><a href="#1-1创建仓库" class="headerlink" title="1.1创建仓库"></a>1.1创建仓库</h3><p>注意：路径格式：你的用户名.github.io</p><h2 id="2-本地：blog-文件夹下"><a href="#2-本地：blog-文件夹下" class="headerlink" title="2.本地：blog 文件夹下"></a>2.本地：blog 文件夹下</h2><h3 id="2-1-安装插件"><a href="#2-1-安装插件" class="headerlink" title="2.1 安装插件"></a>2.1 安装插件</h3><p>cnpm install –save hexo-deployer-git</p><h3 id="2-2-设置-config-yml-文件"><a href="#2-2-设置-config-yml-文件" class="headerlink" title="2.2 设置 _config.yml 文件"></a>2.2 设置 _config.yml 文件</h3><p>vscode中 打开这个文件，在这个文件最下面找到Deployment</p><h4 id="2-2-1-改type-‘git’"><a href="#2-2-1-改type-‘git’" class="headerlink" title="2.2.1 改type: ‘git’"></a>2.2.1 改type: ‘git’</h4><h4 id="2-2-2-加repo"><a href="#2-2-2-加repo" class="headerlink" title="2.2.2 加repo"></a>2.2.2 加repo</h4><p>repo: ‘仓库地址’</p><h4 id="2-2-3-加branch"><a href="#2-2-3-加branch" class="headerlink" title="2.2.3 加branch"></a>2.2.3 加branch</h4><p>branch: ‘master’</p><h2 id="3-部署到远端"><a href="#3-部署到远端" class="headerlink" title="3.部署到远端"></a>3.部署到远端</h2><p>hexo d</p><p>输入用户名、密码，然后授权</p><hr><h1 id="New-Theme"><a href="#New-Theme" class="headerlink" title="New Theme"></a>New Theme</h1><h2 id="git-clone"><a href="#git-clone" class="headerlink" title="git clone"></a>git clone</h2><p>git clone 克隆的地址.git 位置 themes.名字<br>注意 git clone <a href="https://github.com/litten/hexo-theme-yilia.git">https://github.com/litten/hexo-theme-yilia.git</a> themes.yilia 中的https 改为 git<br>git clone git://github.com/litten/hexo-theme-yilia.git themes/yilia</p><h2 id="set-new-themes-into-blog"><a href="#set-new-themes-into-blog" class="headerlink" title="set new themes into blog"></a>set new themes into blog</h2><h3 id="change-the-file-named-config-yml"><a href="#change-the-file-named-config-yml" class="headerlink" title="change the file named _config.yml"></a>change the file named _config.yml</h3><p>find theme and change theme name with your new theme’s name<br>theme: yilia</p><h2 id="put-into-github-推到远端"><a href="#put-into-github-推到远端" class="headerlink" title="put into github 推到远端"></a>put into github 推到远端</h2><p>首先<br>hexo clean<br>hexo g<br>hexo s<br>最后<br>hexo d</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Start-Hexo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Start-Hexo&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Start Hexo&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Start Hexo&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-cd-the-url-of-hexo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/categories/Hexo/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
