<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Gooooooooooood</title>
  <icon>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/eb4ac5c946da3c1711e5ecff20d94b87</icon>
  
  <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-12-13T12:58:41.311Z</updated>
  <id>https://xuduokuaile.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Xu</name>
    <email>1361696007@qq.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Translation</title>
    <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/13/Translation/"/>
    <id>https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/13/Translation/</id>
    <published>2021-12-13T06:54:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-13T12:58:41.311Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="第一篇"><a href="#第一篇" class="headerlink" title="第一篇"></a>第一篇</h1><p>类似的可能还有毛笔，扇子，镜子等话题。篇幅问题，我就给大家一个。</p><p>筷子(chopsticks ）是中国传统的独具特色的进食工具（dining utensils），至今已有数千年的历史。筷子在古代被称为 “箸”，大约从明朝开始才有了 “筷子 ”的称呼。筷子多为竹子制成，也有用木头、象牙（ ivory）、金属或其他材料制作而成。它要么上方下圆，要么上下全圆而上粗下细。不管其形状如何，筷子必须是成对使用的，并且两只筷子的大小长短要相同。筷子是中国人日常生活的必备工具，它的发明充分反映了中国人民的智慧。</p><p>Chopsticks, with a history of thousands of years, are unique traditional Chinese dining utensils. They were called “zhu” in ancient China and the name of “Kuai Zi” began to be used in Ming Dynasty. Chopsticks are usually made of bamboo. Some are made of wood, ivory, metals or other materials. Their upper parts are squar e and lower parts round, or they are all round with thicker upper parts and thinner lower parts. Whatever their shapes are, they are used in pairs and the pair must be identical to each other. Chopsticks are the necessary dining utensils in Chinese people’s daily life, the invention of which fully displays the intelligence of Chinese people.</p><h1 id="第二篇"><a href="#第二篇" class="headerlink" title="第二篇"></a>第二篇</h1><p>黄梅戏</p><p>类似的还有“京剧”“昆曲”都算，篇幅问题就给大家一篇</p><p>黄梅戏(Huangmei Opera)源于湖北省黄梅县的采茶歌曲，连同京剧、越剧 (Yue Opera)、评剧(Ping Opera)和豫剧(Yu Opera)是中国的五大戏曲。它最初是以一种简单的载歌载舞的戏剧形式出现的。后来，随着饱受洪水灾害的灾民，黄梅戏传到了安徽省安庆市。它吸收了徽剧和当地歌舞的元素，发展到了今天的形式。黄梅戏以一种淸新的风格反映了普通居民的生活，受到了群众的喜爱。</p><p>Huangmei Opera was originated from tea picking songs in Huangmei county,Hubei province. It is one of the Five Operas in China together with Beijing Opera, Yue Opera, Ping Opera and Yu Opera. It first appeared as a simple drama of song and dance.Later, it was spread to Anqing, Anhui Province by immigrating victims of floods. Absorbing elements of Anhui Opera and local songs and dances, Huangmei Opera was developed to the present form. It enjoys great popularity among the masses by reflecting the life of ordinary people in a fresh style.</p><h1 id="第三篇"><a href="#第三篇" class="headerlink" title="第三篇"></a>第三篇</h1><p>水稻</p><p>可能也会考杂交水稻，但是我感觉还是水稻的可能性大一些，类似的还有“小麦”等话题</p><p>在中国，水稻生产是国民经济的重要组成部分，中国人早在公元前4000年就开始了水稻种植，而后逐渐传播到世界各地。目前，中国是世界上最大的水稻生产国，水稻产量占世界产量的26%。我国水稻主要种植于长江沿岸及南方各省份，米饭是中国人，特别是南方人，非常重要的主食。此外，水稻还可以用来酿酒、制糖及用作工业原料。</p><p>In China,rice production is an important part of the national economy.As early as 4,000 B.C.,the Chinese started rice cultivation which later gradually spread all over the world.At present,China is the world’s largest producer of rice,producing 26% of the world rice output.The rice crop in China grows primarily in provinces along the Yangtze River and in the South.Rice is an important staple food for Chinese,particularly the southerners.In addition,rice can be used to make wine and sugar and used as industrial materials.</p><h1 id="第四篇"><a href="#第四篇" class="headerlink" title="第四篇"></a>第四篇</h1><p>类似的可能还有“垃圾分类”等话题</p><p>低碳生活 (low -carbon life) 对于我们普通人来说是一种态度，我们应该积极提倡并去实践，从自己做起，从节约水电这些点滴做起。除了植树，有的人买运输里程很短的商品，还 有人坚持爬楼梯，形 形色色，非 常有趣。“低碳生活”的理念逐渐被世界各国所接受。低碳生活的出现不仅告诉人们可以为减碳做些什么，还告诉人们可以怎么做。在这种生活方式逐渐兴起的时候，大家开始关心自己每天是否为减碳做了什么。</p><p>Low-carbon life is an attitude for ordinary people, an d we should actively advocate and practice low -carbon life by doing it from ourselves and by starting bit by bit from saving water and electricity. Beside s planting trees, some peoplepurchase goods within a short delivery distance and others stick to climbing stairs.People do various things to live a low -carbon life, whic h is really interesting. “Lo w-carbon life “concep t has gradually been accepted worldwi de. The emergence of low -carbon lifestyle not only introduces to people what they can do for carbon reduction,but also tells them how they can do it. As this lifestyle gradually becomes popular,people begin to ask themselves whether they have contributed something to carbon reduction every day.</p><hr><h1 id="第一篇相似"><a href="#第一篇相似" class="headerlink" title="第一篇相似"></a>第一篇相似</h1><p>毛笔，是一种源于中国的传统书写工具，也逐渐成为传统绘画工具。毛笔是汉族人民在生产实践中发明的。随着人类社会的不断发展，勤劳智慧的汉民族又不断地总结经验，存其精华，弃其糟粕，勇于探索，敢于创新。几千年以来，它为创造汉族民族光辉灿烂的文化，为促进汉民族与世界各族的文化交流，做出了卓越的贡献。毛笔是汉民族对世界艺术宝库提供的一件珍宝。</p><p>　　【参考译文】</p><p>　　Writing brush, a traditional writing tool originated from China, has also gradually become a traditional painting tool. Writing brush was invented by the Han people during their production practice. With the constant development of human society, the diligent and intelligent Han people kept summing up the experience. Discarding the dross while assimilating the essence, they strive to explore and blaze new trails. Over thousands of years, writing brush has made great contribution to creating the splendid culture of the Han people and to promoting the cultural exchange between people of all nationalities and the Han people. Writing brush is a treasure that the Han people have provided the world’s arts treasure house.</p><p>在中国，扇子的使用始于数千年前。扇子是由许多不同的材料制成的。汉、唐期间，农业有了发展，丝绸和缎面(satin)扇子开始出现，并在文人雅士 (scholars and artists)中成为了一种时尚。他们通过在扇面上书写和绘画来展示自己的才能。扇子很快获得了非常大的社会意义。它们成为了有学问的人标准夏季着装的一部分。中国制作的扇子多种多样。它们如今依旧享有盛誉。</p><p>　　参考翻译:</p><p>　　Fans began to be used in China thousands of years ago. They were made out of many different materials. During the Han and Tang Dynasties, due to progress in agriculture, silk and satin fans appeared, and they became a fashion among scholars and artists who showed their genius by writing and painting on the fans. Fans soon acquired considerable social significance. They became a part of the standard summer costume among the learned. A great variety of fans have been produced in China and they still enjoy great reputation today.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;第一篇&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#第一篇&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;第一篇&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;第一篇&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;类似的可能还有毛笔，扇子，镜子等话题。篇幅问题，我就给大家一个。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;筷子(chopsticks ）是中国传统的独具特色的</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="English Learning" scheme="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Writting Skill for Band 6</title>
    <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/10/writting-skill-in-Band-6/"/>
    <id>https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/10/writting-skill-in-Band-6/</id>
    <published>2021-12-10T09:01:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-13T06:51:14.364Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="1-find-writting-task"><a href="#1-find-writting-task" class="headerlink" title="1 find writting task"></a>1 find writting task</h2><p>why?, what? or how? .</p><hr><h2 id="2-beginning"><a href="#2-beginning" class="headerlink" title="2 beginning"></a>2 beginning</h2><h3 id="2-1矛盾"><a href="#2-1矛盾" class="headerlink" title="2.1矛盾"></a>2.1矛盾</h3><p>The last few years have witnessed the trend of…  +状语—时间地点原因目的//背景 加一些个性化的东西，this increasingly globalised world<br>When it comes to whether…, people harbour divergent viewpoints on… .  //双方 注意主题同义替换<br>Some believe that … , while others hold the idea that … . //具体<br>However, from my perspective,  I stand for the former/latter one. //我的观点 </p><h3 id="2-2重要性"><a href="#2-2重要性" class="headerlink" title="2.2重要性"></a>2.2重要性</h3><p>The last few years have witnessed the trend of… +状语—时间地点原因目的//背景<br>Were it not for …, … would be seriously undermined. //要不是…(if it were not)，…将会受到极大影响。<br>Were it not for …, it would be harder for to //要不是…(if it were not)，将很难做..。<br>Nothing is more principle than… //什么是十分重要的</p><h3 id="2-3名言"><a href="#2-3名言" class="headerlink" title="2.3名言"></a>2.3名言</h3><p>The last few years have witnessed the trend of… +状语—时间地点原因目的//背景<br>As a famous saying/proverb goes，… //谚语<br>From my perspective, this proverb tell us that we cannot … unless … // 我们不能…，除非…</p><h3 id="2-4社会现象"><a href="#2-4社会现象" class="headerlink" title="2.4社会现象"></a>2.4社会现象</h3><p>It is quite common for sb. to do sth+ 状语—时间地点原因目的//背景<br>To illustrate, we can often that… //简而言之<br>Obviously, this issue has already given rise to a lot of public concerns so </p><h3 id="2-5漫画"><a href="#2-5漫画" class="headerlink" title="2.5漫画"></a>2.5漫画</h3><p>As is explicitly demonstrated in the cartoon, A is doing … and B say with doubt/certainty/irony … //正如漫画清楚描述的那样,A…B迟疑地/确定地/讽刺地回复<br>Then, A looks embarrassed/frustrated/disappointed. //A看起来很尴尬/沮丧/不开心<br>Apparently, this cartoon aims to tell us that in order to …, sb should … </p><h3 id="2-6图表"><a href="#2-6图表" class="headerlink" title="2.6图表"></a>2.6图表</h3><p>The line/bar/pie chart illustrae how many … from … in … to … in …<br>From the marked/sharp rise/decline in the chart, it goes without saying that</p><hr><hr><p>三篇模板</p><h2 id="第一篇"><a href="#第一篇" class="headerlink" title="第一篇"></a>第一篇</h2><p>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write a composition on the topic “The advantages and disadvantages of online course”.</p><p>除了网课，网络和科技相关的话题也有可能考到，但是换汤不换药，按照我讲的结构写就OK。六级写作最好能举一个例子</p><p>（其实网课之前考过，不排除不会再考，只是形式会变换）</p><p>It has been widely noted that the Internet has penetrated every aspect of our daily life and exerted a huge impact on our study.Online course which is held by many to be an indispensable tool,has captured public attention.</p><p>As regards to the social implication of Online course,my discussion on the issue is mainly twofold.On the one hand,due to the outbreak of the novel coronavirus, the city where I lived was on lockdown. We needed to be quarantined at home. However, the Internet allowed us to take online courses, bringing much convenience to our education.Thus studying online is a wise choice to meet the needs of offline learning.On the other hand,Online course only suits students with good self-control instead of those who have difficulty in self-discipline.Meanwhile,it relies too much on media, which can easily divert students’ attention from their study.Finally,it’s difficult for learners to organize teamwork and develop impersonal relationships through distance learning.</p><p>To sum up, it is of great benefit for us to attend online course reasonably and learn how to make the most of it.Specifically,The fundamental way in which the school should make full use of the advantages of network courses to promote the all-round development of students.</p><h2 id="第二篇"><a href="#第二篇" class="headerlink" title="第二篇"></a>第二篇</h2><p>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write a composition on the topic“How to Balance Compulsory and Selective Courses”</p><p>In view of students’ comprehensive development, most universities offer a wide range of selective courses as the complement to compulsory courses.</p><p>However, this well-intentioned design brings about some unexpected problems. One problem to note is that despite the freedom to choose what to learn, students are still required to complete the selective courses with credits, which means they have to put in extra energy and time in order to meet the requirements. This gives rise to a problem of how to strike a balance between compulsory and selective course and many complaints are heard among college students who find it hard to struggle for excellent performance in both selective courses and compulsory courses.</p><p>From my point of view, the key to this problem lies in the time management. All that a student needs to do is to make the time distribution between the study of compulsory and selective courses more reasonable. When there is a scientifically-arranged schedule to follow, I believe students will do better when facing the academic challenges, be it compulsory or selective courses.</p><h2 id="第三篇"><a href="#第三篇" class="headerlink" title="第三篇"></a>第三篇</h2><p>Directions: For this part, you are allowed 30 minutes to write a composition on the importance of persistence/cooperation/optimism.（价值观方面，例如个人努力，个人习惯，沟通表达等）</p><p>In such a competitive society,it goes without saying that persistence is of utmost importance in our study and life. persistence has become an integral part for great achievements and this character has obviously shaped our culture and destiny in quite an obvious manner.</p><p>As regards the social implication of this spirit, my discussion is generally twofold.On the one hand,against the backdrop of ruthless and fierce competition,persistence is truly the fundamental attribute of top performers,which separates the high achievers from the rest of the pack.On the other hand,persistence can not only enable us to ameliorate ourselves so that we can be qualified for future career promotion,but also make us be ready for meeting the for the coming challenges.We students should never give up our dreams in face of hardship.For example Chinese scientist Tu Youyou,the first Chinese female Nobel Prize winner,managed to combined traditional Chinese medicine and western medicine innovatively to obtain the pure substance qinghaosu.if she had given up when she were confronted with challenges.It is no exaggeration to say that It was unswerving persistence that made her become one of the greatest scientists in human history.</p><p>To sum up,we can come to the conclusion that the persistence is of equal importance in personal and social progress.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-find-writting-task&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-find-writting-task&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;1 find writting task&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;1 find writting task&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="English Learning" scheme="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Start Hexo</title>
    <link href="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/08/start-hexo/"/>
    <id>https://xuduokuaile.github.io/2021/12/08/start-hexo/</id>
    <published>2021-12-08T12:59:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-12T12:17:54.963Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Start-Hexo"><a href="#Start-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="Start Hexo"></a>Start Hexo</h1><h2 id="1-cd-the-url-of-hexo"><a href="#1-cd-the-url-of-hexo" class="headerlink" title="1. cd the url of hexo"></a>1. cd the url of hexo</h2><p>cd the url of hexo</p><h2 id="2-hexo-s"><a href="#2-hexo-s" class="headerlink" title="2. hexo s"></a>2. hexo s</h2><hr><h1 id="Writing-an-Article"><a href="#Writing-an-Article" class="headerlink" title="Writing an Article"></a>Writing an Article</h1><h2 id="1-创建新的文件"><a href="#1-创建新的文件" class="headerlink" title="1.创建新的文件"></a>1.创建新的文件</h2><p>hexo n  + 文章名</p><h2 id="2-编写内容"><a href="#2-编写内容" class="headerlink" title="2.编写内容"></a>2.编写内容</h2><p>最好使用 markdown 格式</p><h2 id="3-清理缓存文件"><a href="#3-清理缓存文件" class="headerlink" title="3.清理缓存文件"></a>3.清理缓存文件</h2><p>hexo clean</p><h2 id="4-生成静态文件"><a href="#4-生成静态文件" class="headerlink" title="4.生成静态文件"></a>4.生成静态文件</h2><p>hexo g</p><hr><h1 id="Link-to-GitHub"><a href="#Link-to-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Link to GitHub"></a>Link to GitHub</h1><h2 id="1-远端：github"><a href="#1-远端：github" class="headerlink" title="1.远端：github"></a>1.远端：github</h2><h3 id="1-1创建仓库"><a href="#1-1创建仓库" class="headerlink" title="1.1创建仓库"></a>1.1创建仓库</h3><p>注意：路径格式：你的用户名.github.io</p><h2 id="2-本地：blog-文件夹下"><a href="#2-本地：blog-文件夹下" class="headerlink" title="2.本地：blog 文件夹下"></a>2.本地：blog 文件夹下</h2><h3 id="2-1-安装插件"><a href="#2-1-安装插件" class="headerlink" title="2.1 安装插件"></a>2.1 安装插件</h3><p>cnpm install –save hexo-deployer-git</p><h3 id="2-2-设置-config-yml-文件"><a href="#2-2-设置-config-yml-文件" class="headerlink" title="2.2 设置 _config.yml 文件"></a>2.2 设置 _config.yml 文件</h3><p>vscode中 打开这个文件，在这个文件最下面找到Deployment</p><h4 id="2-2-1-改type-‘git’"><a href="#2-2-1-改type-‘git’" class="headerlink" title="2.2.1 改type: ‘git’"></a>2.2.1 改type: ‘git’</h4><h4 id="2-2-2-加repo"><a href="#2-2-2-加repo" class="headerlink" title="2.2.2 加repo"></a>2.2.2 加repo</h4><p>repo: ‘仓库地址’</p><h4 id="2-2-3-加branch"><a href="#2-2-3-加branch" class="headerlink" title="2.2.3 加branch"></a>2.2.3 加branch</h4><p>branch: ‘master’</p><h2 id="3-部署到远端"><a href="#3-部署到远端" class="headerlink" title="3.部署到远端"></a>3.部署到远端</h2><p>hexo d</p><p>输入用户名、密码，然后授权</p><hr><h1 id="New-Theme"><a href="#New-Theme" class="headerlink" title="New Theme"></a>New Theme</h1><h2 id="git-clone"><a href="#git-clone" class="headerlink" title="git clone"></a>git clone</h2><p>git clone 克隆的地址.git 位置 themes.名字<br>注意 git clone <a href="https://github.com/litten/hexo-theme-yilia.git">https://github.com/litten/hexo-theme-yilia.git</a> themes.yilia 中的https 改为 git<br>git clone git://github.com/litten/hexo-theme-yilia.git themes/yilia</p><h2 id="set-new-themes-into-blog"><a href="#set-new-themes-into-blog" class="headerlink" title="set new themes into blog"></a>set new themes into blog</h2><h3 id="change-the-file-named-config-yml"><a href="#change-the-file-named-config-yml" class="headerlink" title="change the file named _config.yml"></a>change the file named _config.yml</h3><p>find theme and change theme name with your new theme’s name<br>theme: yilia</p><h2 id="put-into-github-推到远端"><a href="#put-into-github-推到远端" class="headerlink" title="put into github 推到远端"></a>put into github 推到远端</h2><p>首先<br>hexo clean<br>hexo g<br>hexo s<br>最后<br>hexo d</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Start-Hexo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Start-Hexo&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Start Hexo&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Start Hexo&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-cd-the-url-of-hexo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://xuduokuaile.github.io/categories/Hexo/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
